THAT is the movie!
To Be or Not to Be is a comedy, drama, war film directed by Alan Johnson.
A bad Polish actor is just trying to make a living when
Poland is invaded by the Germans in World War II.
His wife has the habit of entertaining young Polish officers while he's
on stage, which is also a source of depression to him.
When one of her officers comes back on a Secret Mission, the actor
takes charge and comes up with a plan for them to escape.
Dr. Frederick Bronski, played by Mel Brooks.
Anna Bronski, played by Anne Bancroft.
Lt. Andre Sobinski, played by Tim Matheson.
Col. Erhardt, played by Charles Durning.
Prof. Siletski, played by José Ferrer.
Ravitch, played by George Gaynes.
To Be or Not to Be is a 1983 American war comedy film directed by Alan Johnson, produced by Mel Brooks, and
starring Brooks, Anne Bancroft, Tim Matheson, Charles Durning, Christopher Lloyd, and José Ferrer.
The screenplay was written by Ronny Graham and Thomas Meehan, based on the original
story by Melchior Lengyel, Ernst Lubitsch and Edwin Justus Mayer.
The film is a remake of the 1942 film of the same name.
The film explores themes of nazi, world war ii,
parody, remake, polish stereotype.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.